<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Mijndert Stuij</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/</link><description>Recent content on Mijndert Stuij</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://mijndertstuij.nl/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>4 apps I use for information processing</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2021/4-apps-i-use-for-information-processing/</link><pubDate>Mon, 15 Feb 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2021/4-apps-i-use-for-information-processing/</guid><description>Ever since this COVID-19 thing hit I&amp;rsquo;ve been working from home non-stop. That&amp;rsquo;s almost a full year of working remotely and being fully in charge of my own productivity. To be honest, I could keep this going forever - I&amp;rsquo;ve never been more productive in my life.
The last few months have also been perfect to optimize certain aspects of my work, the most important one being information processing. I&amp;rsquo;ve been horrible at keeping track of todo items before since I could never make it stick.</description></item><item><title>Automating Digitalocean using Terraform</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/automating-digitalocean-using-terraform/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/automating-digitalocean-using-terraform/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been an AWS engineer/consultant for 13 years already, but Digitalocean will always be my go-to for personal projects. AWS is usually too complicated and expensive a platform for my needs. Sometimes I just need a quick VM to test some stuff out, or get something on the internet quickly.
I&amp;rsquo;ve had a shell script that bootstraps my Linux VM&amp;rsquo;s for the longest time, it installs a bunch of packages, creates users, configures the timezone and much more.</description></item><item><title>Publishing thoughts using Jekyll</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/publishing-thoughts-using-jekyll/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/publishing-thoughts-using-jekyll/</guid><description>Jekyll has been my static website generator for years now. I understand every little detail of its inner workings and I can create my own themes and plug-ins if needed. Jekyll allows for an incredible amount of control, something I would have to give up had I used WordPress or some other CMS. Jekyll also allows me to create websites that perform very well, and I always strive for a score of 100 on Lighthouse.</description></item><item><title>What the second half of this crazy year has on offer</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/what-the-second-half-of-this-crazy-year-has-on-offer/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/what-the-second-half-of-this-crazy-year-has-on-offer/</guid><description>The first half of this year has been relentless in its weirdness. The COVID-19 crisis has thrown most plans out the window, but also opened doors to previously unexplored terrain. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working from home for most of the year and the new normal is just now settling in a bit.
Working from home has mostly blurred the lines between work and private life, which made me reconsider what&amp;rsquo;s really important, just to keep myself and my loved ones sane.</description></item><item><title>I can't possibly begin to imagine what it's like</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/i-cant-possibly-begin-to-imagine-what-its-like/</link><pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/i-cant-possibly-begin-to-imagine-what-its-like/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;m a white male living in Europe. I can&amp;rsquo;t possibly begin to imagine what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be black.
What I can do however, is try to imagine what it does to a person to live in constant fear of not making it home.
Imagine what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be turned away from schools, internships, jobs.
Imagine what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be framed.
Imagine what it&amp;rsquo;s like to be shot at while you&amp;rsquo;re driving your pregnant wife to the hospital.</description></item><item><title>Creating a workflow for Terraform using GitHub Actions</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/creating-a-workflow-for-terraform-using-github-actions/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/creating-a-workflow-for-terraform-using-github-actions/</guid><description>Recently I started working with Terraform more and more, as CloudFormation is lagging behind in terms of support for newer AWS services. Terraform has quite a steep learning curve, but once it clicks you never want to go back to the old days.
I created a public repository up on GitHub so I can play around with Terraform and other related tools. This week GitHub Satellite is on, which brought us a much needed feature: a proper GitHub Action for working with Terraform in a CI/CD pipeline.</description></item><item><title>How I integrated Tmux into my workflow</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/how-i-integrated-tmux-into-my-workflow/</link><pubDate>Thu, 16 Apr 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/how-i-integrated-tmux-into-my-workflow/</guid><description>Tmux is a terminal multiplexer. It lets you switch between several programs through windows and panes, detach your session and reattach to it on a different computer. I reckon it&amp;rsquo;s mostly used on servers where people have long running jobs and such running in a tmux session.
The learning curve is what always withheld me from just diving in and giving Tmux a chance to get integrated into my workflow. I wanted to share some of the small changes I made to my Tmux configuration to make life a little easier.</description></item><item><title>Things I've learnt while setting up a GitHub repository</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/coordination/</link><pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2020/coordination/</guid><description>For the past few weeks I&amp;rsquo;ve been planning and working on a new project. It&amp;rsquo;s not a very novel idea but it&amp;rsquo;s something I want to exist and I&amp;rsquo;m hoping others will get some value out of it as well.
As I want this project to be bigger than just myself I wanted to make sure the project is set up for easy managent and automation. I made use of just about every trick GitHub has on offer, like issue labels, projects, and GitHub Actions.</description></item><item><title>What I think minimalism is and isn't</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2019/purpose/</link><pubDate>Mon, 28 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2019/purpose/</guid><description>Places like Reddit and Twitter are filled with people who practice their version of minimalism. The most prevalent method is to just have less of everything. Some groups of people even go so far as to think they can only have a fixed amount of things in their lives.
Don&amp;rsquo;t let anyone tell you this is the spirit of minimalism because it&amp;rsquo;s not. Let me explain.
I&amp;rsquo;ve always practiced minimalism, even way before I knew about the term.</description></item><item><title>Your television is spying on you</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2019/your-television-is-spying-on-you/</link><pubDate>Wed, 09 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2019/your-television-is-spying-on-you/</guid><description>I have known for a very long time that today&amp;rsquo;s televisions are sending data back home at an unprecedented scale. Companies like Samsung make tv&amp;rsquo;s so cheap, you have to be the product one way or the other. We have a Sony set running Android so it&amp;rsquo;s bound to send data back too - it&amp;rsquo;s in the nature of the software it&amp;rsquo;s running. Even if we&amp;rsquo;re not using the built-in OS it will know when I&amp;rsquo;ve selected the HDMI input for my Xbox, I&amp;rsquo;m sure.</description></item><item><title>Guiding principles for the coming year</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2019/2019/</link><pubDate>Mon, 07 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/thought/2019/2019/</guid><description> Experiences over possessions Spend less money on useless things Read more books Travel more Get rid of distractions Do what I say I&amp;rsquo;m gonna do Be more mindful of (potential) health issues Share experiences with others Write Use less social media Take more photos Have less fucks to give Always start with first principles thinking Put my phone away Keep only the essential apps Take time to step back and appreciate what I have Count to 10 Do more things for myself Stop worrying about what others will think Delegate more Ask questions</description></item><item><title>AWS explained</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/aws/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/aws/</guid><description>This is a continually updated page. You can contribute on GitHub.
In the old world you had to do extensive research into the right equipment that would hopefully meet all of your demands. Then you had to order the hardware, which would take another month, and then someone had to install and configure the equipment. Provisioning a bunch of servers would easily take a few months. We&amp;rsquo;re now building an entirely new class of infrastructure and democratizing them so anyone has access to them.</description></item><item><title>Uses</title><link>https://mijndertstuij.nl/uses/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://mijndertstuij.nl/uses/</guid><description>If you&amp;rsquo;re anything like me you probably love to talk about the tools that you use to do your work every day. This page serves as a living document of just that.
Software Firefox — Mozilla isn&amp;rsquo;t a perfect company, but I stick with Firefox to combat the mono-engine internet. Terminal — Recently switched back to Terminal from iTerm2 since Tmux is all I need really. Dracula as the color scheme and Jetbrains Mono as the font.</description></item></channel></rss>